Register of the Bolivian subject collection, 1944-1989
Hoover Institution Archives
Bolivian Subject Collection,
1944-1989
XX795
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings, pamphlets, reports, and other printed matter, relating to political conditions in Bolivia, and especially to the Bolivian revolution of 1946.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Bolivia--Politics and government; Bolivia--History--Revolution, 1946; Bolivia
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- SUBJECT FILE, 1949-1989.
  Pamphlets, reports, serial issues, documents, statutes, programs, leaflets, bibliography and clippings, mainly relating to political and social conditions, arranged alphabetically by subject
  See card catalog for increments that may have been added since December 1994.
CONTAINER LIST
- SUBJECT FILE, 1949-1989.
  - General
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Pamphlets, serial issues, leaflets and bibliography, mainly relating to political and social conditions, 1975-1985. Includes material concerning exile groups, foreign policy issues, peasant movements, the Catholic church, and the Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria (MIR)
    - Speeches by Presidents Banzer Suarez, Gueiler Tejada, Meza Tejada and Padilla Arancibia, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Elections, 1980 and 1989. Reports, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Partido Comunista de Bolivia. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Statutes, programs, pamphlets, articles and documents, 1978-1986.Includes material relating to party congress
  - Revolution, 1946.
    Press clippings relating to the government of Gualberto Villarroel and its subsequent overthrow, 1944-1946
    - Volume One. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Concerning opposition to the government of Villarroel, 1944-1945
    - Volume Two. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Concerning opposition to the government of Villarroel, 1946
    - Volume Three. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Material relating to the antecedents and events of the revolution of July 21, 1946
    - Volume Four. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Material relating to political disorder, the government of Tomas Monje Gutierrez, and the deaths of Majors Eguino and Escobar and Lieutenant Oblitas in La Paz, 1946